<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>taskcluster on Hunting the Shmoo</title>
    <link>https://ahal.ca/tags/taskcluster/</link>
    <description>Recent content in taskcluster on Hunting the Shmoo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2018 Andrew Halberstadt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 12:08:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ahal.ca/tags/taskcluster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Firefox More Efficiently With Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://ahal.ca/blog/2020/testing-firefox-more-efficiently-with-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 12:08:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahal.ca/blog/2020/testing-firefox-more-efficiently-with-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was co-authored with &lt;a href=&#34;https://marco-c.github.io/&#34;&gt;Marco Castelluccio&lt;/a&gt;, and was originally
posted to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/07/testing-firefox-more-efficiently-with-machine-learning/&#34;&gt;Mozilla Hacks
Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A browser is an incredibly complex piece of software. With such enormous complexity, the only way to maintain a rapid pace of development is through an extensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_integration&#34;&gt;CI&lt;/a&gt; system that can give developers confidence that their changes won&amp;rsquo;t introduce bugs. Given the scale of our CI, we’re always looking for ways to reduce load while maintaining a high standard of product quality. We wondered if we could use machine learning to reach a higher degree of efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using One Click Loaner to Debug Failures</title>
      <link>https://ahal.ca/blog/2016/taskcluster-interactive-loaner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahal.ca/blog/2016/taskcluster-interactive-loaner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most painful aspects of a developer&amp;rsquo;s work cycle is trying to fix failures that show up
on try, but which can&amp;rsquo;t be reproduced locally. When this happens, there were really only two
options (neither of them nice):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You could spam try with print debugging. But this isn&amp;rsquo;t very powerful, and takes forever to get
feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You could request a loaner from releng. But this is a heavy handed process, and once you have the
loaner it is very hard to get tests up and running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce there is now a third option, which is easy, powerful and 100% self-serve.
Rather than trying to explain it in words, here is a ~5 minute demo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>