<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devops on Hunting the Shmoo</title>
    <link>https://ahal.ca/tags/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devops on Hunting the Shmoo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2018 Andrew Halberstadt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 11:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ahal.ca/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DevOps at Mozilla</title>
      <link>https://ahal.ca/blog/2021/mozilla-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahal.ca/blog/2021/mozilla-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first joined &lt;a href=&#34;https://ahal.ca/blog/2011/why-mozilla-is-awesome/&#34;&gt;Mozilla as an intern&lt;/a&gt; in 2010 for
the &amp;ldquo;Tools and Automation Team&amp;rdquo; (colloquially called the &amp;ldquo;A-Team&amp;rdquo;). I always had a bit of
difficulty describing our role. We work on tests. But not the tests themselves, the the thing that
runs the tests. Also we make sure the tests run when code lands. Also we have this dashboard to view
results, oh and also we do a bunch of miscellaneous developer productivity kind of things. Oh and
sometimes we have to do other operational type things as well, but it varies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years the team grew to a peak of around 25 people and the A-Team&amp;rsquo;s responsibilities
expanded to include things like the build system, version control, review tools and
more. Combined with Release Engineering (RelEng), this covered almost all of
the software development pipeline. The A-Team was eventually split up into many smaller
teams. Over time those smaller teams were re-org&amp;rsquo;ed, split up further, merged and renamed over and
over again. Many labels were applied to the departments that tended to contain those teams. Labels
like &amp;ldquo;Developer Productivity&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Platform Operations&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Product Integrity&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Engineering
Effectiveness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, from 2010 to present, one label that has never been applied to any of these teams is
&amp;ldquo;DevOps&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
